Beijing Film Studio
Counterattack
Ready!
Move aside!
Ready...
Fire!
Comrade Derong Ding!
Old Ding!
Oh, Comrade Old Geng!
Yes
Everything looks good.
The dam body is stable.
Today’s blast test proves that the “three-in-one combination's” plan—opening the bottom outlet and tunnel—is fully feasible.
This way, the silt in the reservoir can be flushed out.
Ha ha! This is the result of open-door education, learning from the working class!
Ha ha, that’s right.
Hey, Dachuang, hurry!
Auntie Tian brought mung bean sweet soup!
Then let everyone take a break.
Auntie Tian!
Hey, Dachuang! Students, come over!
It’s hot today. Have some mung bean soup and fresh cucumbers!
Students: Auntie!
Thank you auntie!
Pass it out.
Wow, Shen Niu, this soup is exactly what I need!
Auntie, another bowl, please!
Drink up, kids. Today, Auntie’s treating everyone!
Sister Xiao Hong, there are fresh cucumbers too!
Dolma, here. You drink the soup. I like cucumbers.
Xiao Hong, don’t eat the whole basket!
Save some for Jiang Tao. He's loved cucumbers since childhood.
I picked extra just for him today.
Auntie Tian, you really spoil Old Jiang!
Oh! Professor Wen!
Come, have a bowl!
Professor Wen, you’re this old and still working with everyone?
Just getting some exercise!
Your open-door education really reaches us poor peasants.
Here,
Ever since foreign experts designed this dam, the reservoir filled up with silt.
Hundreds of thousands of acres of farmland turned salty.
We can’t grow grain or contribute to the country.
It hurts us poor and lower-middle peasants deeply.
Professor Wen: Yes, that’s true.
Auntie Tian: Since Jiang Tao brought you teachers and students here,
you’ve worked with laborers through wind and rain.
All with one goal—to control the reservoir’s silt.
That’s good education from your school!
Professor Wen: Auntie, we still haven’t done enough.
Please guide us more.
Auntie Tian: Guide you?
I just can’t bear to see you leave! Ha ha ha!
Zhong Dachuang: What? Leave?
Auntie Tian: Last night, a few of us stayed up making these.
They’re souvenirs—one for each of you!
Dolma: They’re beautiful!
Zhong Dachuang: "We must do a good job in managing the Yellow River."
Soil?
Auntie, what is this?
Auntie Tian: This is soil from the Yellow River.
It holds poor people’s tears, martyrs’ blood, and peasants’ sweat!
Wherever you go, never forget the Yellow River!
Zhong Dachuang: Auntie, after graduation, we won’t leave! We’ll take root right here!
Auntie Tian: Really?  Everyone: Really!
Auntie Tian: That’s wonderful!
Shen Niu: This is our application to the Party committee. We ask to become peasants after graduation!
Qiao Boren: Look at this—open-door education, and they don’t even want to study!
College graduates becoming workers and peasants? Hmph!
Professor Xue: College graduates as workers and peasants? Ha!
Then why go to college at all?
Yao Mingli: Director Qiao! Professor Xue!
Qiao Boren: Mingli, where have you been?
Yao Mingli: The Provincial Water Resources Bureau transferred me back.
Qiao Boren: Great! Great! Ha ha ha!
Professor Xue: Congratulations on ending your sent-down labor.
Yao Mingli: Thank you. Goodbye.
Qiao Boren: Wasn’t he your top student back then?
Professor Xue: Yes, but Jiang Tao labeled him ideologically reactionary, a typical "bourgeois expert."  He was even struggled against for it!
Honestly, he just read more books.
Today’s students aren’t even half his level.
Dolma: Comrade Jiang Tao,
the cuckoo flies to announce spring,
our words to the Party express sincere wishes.
Jiang Tao: Dolma!
The Yellow River’s depth shows in its waves. A freed serf’s wishes show in action!
My students, you are all messengers of spring!
After storms, flowers will bloom!
I support you. Post them!
Qiao Boren: Old Jiang, look at those big-character posters!
Talking about becoming workers and peasants after graduation!
As leaders, we must guide them in the right direction!
Jiang Tao: Ha ha ha!
Old Qiao, the students wrote them well!
While the Soviet Union tempts youth with privilege,
our worker-peasant-soldier students willingly stand with workers and peasants.
This is unprecedented in education history!
This is an encouraging achievement of studying Marxist theory and criticizing bourgeois right!
Qiao Boren: Jiang Tao, you’re head of the worker propaganda team, Party secretary, and a provincial standing committee member.
You surely know more than we do.
I hear education is about to be “rectified”?
Professor Xue: Hmph!
Jiang Tao: Oh? You’re very sensitive.
Qiao Boren: It's me, Qiao Boren!
Oh—Secretary Song?
What?
Ah?
Excellent! Excellent!
Qiao Boren: Han Xiaofang, come here!
Your father has been reinstated!
Still the First Party Secretary of the province!
Han Xiaofang: Hey!
Qiao Boren: Tomorrow afternoon, the two o’clock flight!
Han Ling: Ha ha ha ha ha!
Comrade Deng Xiaoping invited me to dinner at his home.
He said that after the Cultural Revolution, everything needs rectification.
He told us old fellows: dare to act, and don't be afraid!
Qiao Boren: Ha ha ha!
These eight or nine years weren’t easy.
Han Ling: Indeed. Green hills never age, and clear waters flow eternally. Aren’t I back again?
Qiao Boren: Ha ha ha ha ha!
Han Ling: Xiaoping said rectification must faithfully follow the “three directives.”
Qiao Boren: Great! Education really should be rectified!
Han Ling: Transport, science, and the Four Modernizations all depend on education. Education must not hold them back.
Xiaoping values education greatly. He said the biggest danger now is not studying. Education is where we must start.
Qiao Boren: Start with education?!
Han Ling: Yes. Think carefully about it.
Where did the Cultural Revolution begin, Old Qiao? You must have courage!
Ha ha ha.
Qiao Boren: But what about Jiang Tao at our university?
Han Ling: Don’t worry. The situation is different now. No stone is too hard to block our road!
Lyrics: Facing the bright sun, bearing the Party’s hopes,
Song (lyrics): we worker-peasant-soldier students come from across the motherland…
Han Ling: This is a university? These are college students? Reverse, now!
Secretary Song, notify an emergency provincial meeting! Fully implement Comrade Xiaoping’s directives!
Secretary Song: Yes.
Secretary Song: Let me handle this.
Han Ling: This is outrageous! This approach doesn’t reflect the new spirit. It must be rectified!
Old Old Huang, Today’s meeting was too tense.
Yeah.
Sister Zhao and Jiang Tao’s opinions deserve serious attention.
But rectification and the Three Directives were brought back from Beijing by Party Secretary Han.
Jiang Tao: Sister Zhao, I didn’t expect this wind to blow so fiercely.
Sister Zhao: Yes. Your speech at the meeting was absolutely right.
Jiang Tao: If rectification goes this way, won’t it erase all the gains of the Cultural Revolution?
Sister Zhao: This is fundamentally about one’s attitude toward the Cultural Revolution itself.
Han Ling: Hmph! What should be rectified must be rectified!
Sister Zhao: Your university will be hit first again.
You must be fully prepared.
Jiang Tao: Don’t worry, Sister Zhao. I’m heading back. Goodbye.
Han Ling: Secretary Song? Why doesn’t the dripping water sound as clear as before?
Secretary Song: I’ll check it.
Xiao Lin! Xiao Lin!
How did you adjust this dripping sound? Don’t you know Party Secretary Han can’t sleep if it’s wrong? Fix it immediately!
Secretary Song, where should the sofa go?
Secretary Song: Here. Put it here.
Han Ling: No! Put it exactly where it was before the Cultural Revolution!
Oh, put it there, there.
Secretary Song: Party Secretary Han, Director Qiao and Professor Xue are here.
Han Ling: Old Xue, you’ve heard about rectifying education, right?
Professor Xue: Ha ha. Just rumors.  Qiao Boren: Ha ha. I sensed something.
Han Ling: Human intuition is powerful.
Han Xiaofang: Uncle Qiao, Professor Xue, Dad.
Han Ling: So, how has my worker-peasant-soldier student progressed lately?
Han Xiaofang: We studied theory of dictatorship of the proletariat, and joined class struggle in factories and villages.
Han Ling: I didn’t ask you that!
Han Xiaofang: Oh. We criticized knowledge privatization and elitism. We vowed to become ordinary laborers.
Han Ling: I’m asking about basic theory!
Fluid mechanics. Materials mechanics. Quantum mechanics. How far have you gotten?
Han Xiaofang: Comrade Jiang Tao said combining theory with sediment control helps us remember and apply it better.
Han Ling: Better? This is complete chaos!
If college students all become workers and peasants,
why run universities at all?
It sounds revolutionary, but it’s pure petty-bourgeois fanaticism!
Professor Xue: Yes, yes! Secretary Han is absolutely right!
Qiao Boren: Exactly! Secretary Han, the responsibility isn’t on Xiaofang. Xiaofang has been working hard in his studies.
Xue Yaozong: Right, right! It’s Jiang Tao’s fault, hmph!
Han Ling: Hmm, from now on, listen more to Uncle Qiao and Professor Xue!
Ha ha ha ha!
Professor Xue: Alright, alright! Come eat some apples!
Han Ling: Xiaofang, how much is this big apple in the store?
Han Xiaofang: Forty cents per pound.
Han Ling: And the small one?
Han Xiaofang: Twenty cents.
Han Ling: All apples, but different prices. How can college students equal workers and peasants, hmph!
Education must be rectified!
Qiao Boren: Hmm! I think rectification should start with investigating teaching quality.
Han Ling: Good!
Qiao Boren: Tomorrow, I’ll recall all open-door education students back!
PA: Students, stop and don’t leave! Gather in the main building classroom immediately! Gather in the main building classroom immediately!
Chatter
Xiao Hong: Hey, Dachuang, what meeting is this?
Zhong Dachuang: Don’t know. Professor Wen, do you know?
Professor Wen: Don’t know.
Qiao Boren: Students, quiet! Sit down! Sit down! Be quiet!
Following the provincial leaders’ instructions, to implement the new spirit of education rectification,
we will first investigate teaching quality. Students, time to take a surprise test!
Professor Wen: Why didn’t the Party committee discuss this first?
Professor Wen, Professor Wen. Going to be an exam?
Qiao Boren: Instructor Zhou, please come forward.
Instructor Zhou, distribute the exam papers to everyone.
Um...
Hmm? Go ahead, go ahead!
Professor Xue: Heh heh, let’s do it together.
Professor Wen: Old Xue, who made these questions?
Professor Xue: What?
Professor Wen: Isn’t this basically the same detached approach from before the Cultural Revolution?
Professor Xue: Director Qiao said this is the province’s idea.
Qiao Boren: Alright, no talking!
Now announcing exam rules!
One: No whispering. Two: No looking at books. Three: No extending exam time!
Xiao Hong: Dachuang, did the Party committee discuss this?
Zhong Dachuang: Go find Old Jiang quickly!
(Why is this?)
Professor Xue: Keep yourself together! This is an exam!
Zhong Dachuang: This is a surprise attack! Students, let’s find the Party committee!
Hey, hey hey!?
Qiao Boren: Zhong Dachuang! As a Party committee member, you lead a charge against the exam and disrupt education rectification!
Who are you targeting?
Zhong Dachuang: Whoever backtracks, we aim at them!
Jiang Tao: Well said!  Dachuang’s question deserves thought!
Ha ha.
Old Qiao, doesn’t this exam show problems? Shouldn’t everyone fully express opinions?
Professor Wen: Let me speak. This exam is indeed similar to criticized methods during the Cultural Revolution.
Professor Xue: Oh? Professor Wen, if we connect this exam to denying the Cultural Revolution, others can’t speak!
Qiao Boren: We should face reality. Teaching quality is low, just admit it.
We just need to take real measures to rectify and catch up!
Can’t answer? So you quit the exam? Hmph! That doesn’t solve the problem, right?
Professor Xue: Right, right! Exactly!
If learning is solid and foundations are strong, why fear exams?
Jiang Tao: Fear exams?
Qiao Boren: Comrade Wang Jian, as deputy Party secretary and veteran educator, how can you agree with Jiang Tao’s action?
Wang Jian, Deputy Party Secretary of Yellow River University: Old Qiao, this is not Jiang Tao’s personal opinion. This is the Party committee’s resolution.
Qiao Boren: Fine, fine, I reserve my opinion!
Yaozong, aren’t you feeling unwell? Don’t go!
Professor Xue: I must go. Today is the professors’ meeting. Since the Cultural Revolution, it’s the first of its kind. I must attend!
(Chatter)
Jiang Tao: Comrades, recently fierce debates arose around this exam at our university. Everyone knows the situation.
Allegedly, this exam is meant to investigate teaching quality and implement education rectification.
Since it’s an investigation, it must be comprehensive.
[Agreed voices]
So, after research by the Party committee, today we will also have all present comrades take an exam.
(Discontent voices)
The exam questions are fair and reasonable. We’ll reuse last students’ questions. Students, distribute the papers!
Professor Xue: What? We didn't have time to prepare!
Zhong Dachuang: Ha ha, if you study well and have strong foundations, no need to prepare.
Jiang Tao: Alright, teachers, quiet please. Announcing exam rules:
One, no whispering; Two, no looking at books; Three, no extending exam time.
Professor Wen (writing a poem): Sudden news of exams shocks the heart,
Looking back, yet unaware,
The path returns to correct,
Educational revolution forever green.
Jiang Tao: Alright, comrades, now I announce:
No matter how well you did on the exam, you can keep being professors.
This one exam alone can’t measure your real abilities.
But it proves that the revisionist education path and teaching methods are extremely foolish.
Heh, some say this makes comrades look bad.
Hmph, no. Just taking part in this exam is itself a critique of the revisionist education path.
It reminds me of something that happened thirteen years ago, also in this classroom…
Students: Xiao Hua? What happened? Are you okay?
Go back! Don’t take the exam!
A student: If you don’t take it, you’ll fail the year!
Another student: Fail? You’ll be expelled!
Professor Xue.
Jiang Tao: Someone, take Xiao Hua to the infirmary now!
Professor Xue: Alright, sit down, everyone! Sit down! The exam continues!
Professor Xue.
Jiang Tao: This is inhumane! It destroys youth! Let’s take it to the Party committee!
Principal Qiao! I protest! You don’t care about students’ lives!
A surprise attack, sending so many worker-peasant transfer students away! I protest!
Qiao Boren: Jiang Tao! I announce: starting today,
you are no longer a student of our college. Leave immediately!
Student: Jiang Tao! Jiang Tao! Why?
The factory only sent three of us to college.
If you admit fault to Principal Qiao, you can stay. Our future here is bright!
Jiang Tao: Admit fault? They forced Liu Xiaohua to death! This school is not a place for us!
Think carefully: thirteen years have passed, yet these two exams are exactly the same!
This shows the bourgeoisie trying to replay history’s lesson. We must never allow it!
Everyone, think about what this exam really means!
Isn’t it a denial of the direction of the education revolution? Reversing the verdicts of the Cultural Revolution!
Shen Niu!
Dolma!
Dolma: Xiao Hong! Why didn’t you catch it?
Xiao Hong: Th-this… I wasn’t ready!
Students: Ha ha ha ha!
Zhong Dachuang: Hmph, if you study well and have solid foundations, no need to prepare!
Catch it!
Students: Instructor Zhou! Instructor Zhou!
Sister Zhao: Comrade Jiang Tao, you’ve implemented the new spirit well!
Even failing doesn’t matter. A circle shows learning, we just need to give them more support!
Jiang Tao: Yes, Sister Zhao. The bourgeoisie struck at us, but we blocked it. They won’t be satisfied.
Sister Zhao: Of course, class struggle is getting more complex.
We must watch out for people in our Party sitting on the same bench as the bourgeoisie!
Jiang Tao: Oh, why so happy?
Students: We repelled the bourgeois attack! Of course we’re happy!
We welcome you and Director Zhao to join our victory celebration!
Jiang Tao: Victory should certainly be celebrated.
But this is just a small skirmish, comrades, when the proletariat faces a sudden bourgeois attack!
Students: Good! Keep fighting!
Come on! Move!
Sister Zhao: We must uphold the direction of the education revolution and develop this great momentum!
Jiang Tao: Right. Tomorrow, return the students to the open-door education points.
Instructor Zhou: Goodbye, Comrade Wang Jian. Old Jiang.
Jiang Tao: We must focus on students’ political thinking.
Once at the worksite, make sure to talk with Xiaofang.
Instructor Zhou: Okay, goodbye!
Han Ling: What dance was that just now?
Qiao Boren: “Amei Goes to College.”
Han Ling: Which Amei?
Qiao Boren: Heh, a Miao village girl.
Han Ling: Did she pass the exam? Huh?
Qiao Boren: Exam? Hmph! The first shot went off crooked!
Han Ling: Not crooked. The whole rectification only needs to follow Comrade Xiaoping’s “Three Directives,” Even a crooked shot can hit the mark.
And the press? Has the newspaper editor come?  Secretary Song: He's here.
Please.
Secretary Song: Party Secretary Han’s youngest daughter has been in the countryside for nearly a year. She’s very mindful of political impact, never mentions…
Qiao Boren: No problem! She’ll go to college this year!
Secretary Song: My son happens to be in the same production team as her.
Qiao Boren: Together, then. Do it together.
Newspaper Editor: Here’s the editorial, titled “Education Must Be Rectified, On Taking the Three Directives as the Key Link.”
Han Ling: Mm hmm.
Newspaper Editor: And this is Xiaofang’s big-character poster, “College Students Must Contribute Greatly,” ready to post together tomorrow.
Han Ling: Remove Xiaofang’s name. Replace with “Yellow River College Worker-Peasant-Soldier Students.”
Newspaper Editor: Okay, good. Next: article two on industry,
article three on agriculture, four on science, five on arts.
Han Ling: Posting so many editorials? You don’t understand the art of struggle.
Some issues can be published under the Worker-Peasant-Soldier name.
The goal is comprehensive rectification.
Newspaper Editor: Comrade Han Ling, the People’s Daily and Red Flag magazine never publicized that the Three Directives are the Key Link for comprehensive rectification…
Han Ling: What are you afraid of? Comrade Xiaoping’s instructions aren’t valid?
Also, add this meaning:
Poor education is due to leaders and some people opposing the Party line!
That’s the message. Print it tomorrow!
Ha ha ha ha ha ha!
Professor Xue: Ah, the situation is excellent!
Qiao Boren: Indeed!
Professor Xue: After these eight or nine years, our time has finally come!
Qiao Boren: Ha ha ha ha!
These eight or nine years, we ran fast, caught up with errors!
Ran slow? The errors caught up with us!
Sigh...
Eight or nine years…
Professor Xue: Yellow River source, your youth has returned!
Zhong Dachuang: Han Xiaofang, tell me, what exactly are we rectifying? Why? Where?
Xiao Hong: Tell us! Tell us!
Han Xiaofang: There’s so much to fix! Open-door education, all this chaos!
College students graduating to become workers and peasants? Totally extreme left!
Xiao Hong: Oh, afraid of being like a twenty-cent apple!
Ha ha ha!
Han Xiaofang: Why not?
College students can’t be equated with ordinary workers and peasants!
Instructor Zhou: Xiaofang, you’ve always said:
Learn from workers and peasants. They are the masters of the country.
How is it today that you use the price of goods to explain human relationships?
And compare yourself with workers and peasants as forty-cent and twenty-cent apples?
Don’t you feel ashamed? Where did you even pick up this nonsense?
Han Xiaofang: The new spirit from the Central Committee, do you understand?
Dolma: What new spirit? Isn’t it just your father’s spirit?
Shen Niu: Hmph, the once-famous capitalist roader in the province, I see, hasn’t changed much!
Han Xiaofang: What? You dare oppose the spirit of rectification? And slander veteran cadres? You?
Shen Niu: I ask you, do the May 7th Directive, the July 21st Directive, and Chairman Mao’s long-standing teachings still count?
Han Xiaofang: Now the Three Directives are the core!
Shen Niu: Three Directives as the Key Link?
Instructor Zhou: The provincial paper says the Three Directives are the Key Link. I don’t quite agree.
Professor Wen: Yes, for some people, they do whatever the Cultural Revolution criticized,
and oppose whatever the Cultural Revolution supported. Truly worthless!
Speaking of, has Jiang Tao gone home recently?
Instructor Zhou: Yes, and he asked about our factory too.
Flattop: My fellow workers, have you read the papers recently? Open-door education has many problems!
The Provincial Committee says Yellow River College's sediment discharge plan lacks scientific basis!
So the gate-lifting equipment will not be built!
Workers: Then what about the sediment in the reservoir?
Flattop: The Provincial Committee decided to import dredgers for sand removal.
Instructor Zhou: Wasn’t that the plan criticized during the Cultural Revolution?
Flattop: I don’t know! It’s the province’s decision!
Workers: The province’s decision is wrong!
Professor Wen: Comrades, they want to hit two targets with one shot!
One is to stop the factory's production, the other is to end the education revolution.
Which is Impossible!
Comrades, let’s keep working!
Jiang Tao: They completely deny that human history over thousands of years is a history of class struggle;
They deny the proletariat’s class struggle against the bourgeoisie;
They deny the proletariat’s revolution and dictatorship over the bourgeoisie.
Dad.
Xiao Mei, why aren't you asleep?
Xiao Mei: Daddy, come, I want to ask you something!
What does “rectification” mean?
Jiang Tao: Oh, Xiao Mei, who told you that?
Xiao Mei: Our school teachers argued. Teacher Wang said rectification is good,
Teacher Li said rectification is bad. So which is it?
Jiang Tao: Oh, what do you think?
Xiao Mei: I say it’s bad.
Teacher Wang said, after rectification, when we grow up, we can go to college without going to the countryside.
Jiang Tao: Alright, sleep now.
Rectification is opposing what Chairman Mao said, resisting new things. Of course it’s bad.
Xiao Mei: So you also oppose rectification?
Jiang Tao: Yes, I oppose it too.
Ha ha ha.
Xiao Mei: Daddy, do you guys argue too?
Jiang Tao: No, it’s struggle!
Xiao Mei: Then I want to struggle too!
Jiang Tao: Ha ha ha.
Come in. Oh, Comrade Wang Jian! So late, still awake?
Wang Jian: Weren’t you awake too?
Jiang Tao: Ha ha ha ha, the bourgeoisie won’t let us sleep!
Wang Jian: Secretary Song from the Provincial Committee called,
asking us to reprint the provincial editorial and Xiaofang’s big-character poster in this issue.
Jiang Tao: I've heard. How about your opinion?
Wang Jian: I repeatedly studied Chairman Mao’s teachings, reviewed the path of the past eight or nine years, and I’m convinced their approach is wrong.
But I don’t understand why they proposed the "Three Directives as the Key Link."
Jiang Tao: At the beginning, I often wondered about this too.
My head hurt thinking!
I consulted Marx, Lenin, and Mao,
and studied counter-examples like Bukharin, Khrushchev, Liu Shaoqi, Lin Biao.
One exam, one provincial newspaper, made me clearly see:
They raised the black flags of “class struggle extinguished” and “productive forces determinism" to attack us again.
Wang Jian: You mean?
Jiang Tao: Fully reprint the 16 May Notification and confront them directly!
Wang Jian: Good. And Red Flag magazine, see! The article criticizing Song Jiang the surrenderist is very targeted.
Jiang Tao: Also, select a few big-character posters from the worker-peasant-soldier students and publish them in this issue!
Passerby: Hey, comrades, please line up.
Instructor Zhou: Sorry, I have to catch a train.
Newsstand Clerk: Comrade, here’s your change.
Instructor Zhou: Why is the school journal publishing the 16 May Notification now? They must be up to something!
To me, this goes against the provincial paper’s “Three Directives as the Key Link"!
Flattop: Provincial Paper, anyone wants it?
Anyone read the provincial paper? The provincial paper has the new spirit!
Come on, comrades, read the paper!
Hey, comrades, read the paper!
The provincial paper is free! Free!
Hey, comrades, read the paper! Free!
Song Secretary: Party Secretary Han, it’s chaos! Chaos! The whole city is in disorder!
This is a provincial theoretical publication. What if it reaches Vice Premier Deng?
Han Ling: Hmm? Any reaction?
Song Secretary: Some say, when you compare the 16 May Notification with “Three Directives as the Key Link,” it seems off. It looks like someone wants to alter the Party’s line.
Han Ling: Who? Who do they say wants to alter it?
Song Secretary: They say the journal reprinted an article from Red Flag magazine, and people keep asking:
Who are the modern surrenderists?
Who, outside the 108 heroes of Liangshan, betrayed?
Who turned the Hall of Rebellion into the Hall of Loyalty? Altering the Party’s line?
Who accepted amnesty and then attacked Fang La, suppressing revolutionary rebels?
Han Ling: Who, who? Don’t worry about the ancients!
Now it’s about stability and unity. No surrenderists exist!
Song Secretary: But publishing Chairman Mao’s comments now, the Water Margin instructions must have meaning. I worry…
Han Ling: Overly sensitive! Your name is Song Bin, not Song Jiang!
Go immediately to investigate the journal’s background.
Anyone attacking the “Three Directives as the Key Link” must be strictly dealt with, firmly suppressed!
Also, this issue of the journal must stop circulating immediately!
Crowd: Why stop selling? Why stop selling?
There must be copies here!
Why stop?
Students: Step aside, comrades, here comes the journal!
Comrades, step aside. We’re delivering to the newsstand. If you want to buy, queue at the stand!
Crowd: They’re not selling!
See, they’ve hung the “Stop Selling” sign!
Students: Not selling? Dachuang, let’s sell! Alright, we’ll sell!
Yumei: Old Jiang! Old Jiang!
Jiang Tao: Yumei? What’s the matter?
Yumei: Old Jiang, the province removed Comrade Old Geng, Deputy Director of the Revolutionary Committee!
They even said they might expel him from the Party!
Jiang Tao: On what grounds?
Yumei: Because Comrade old Geng led everyone to study a few articles reprinted in this issue of the journal,
and raised different views on the “Three Directives as the Key Link.”
Yumei: They claim old Geng incited workers, opposed the provincial committee, opposed the Party, opposed the Central Committee!
Students: Old Jiang! Old Jiang! Dachuang was captured by a gang of bad guys!
Jiang Tao: Where?
Students: At the newsstand, while selling journals, a guy with flattop led a gang, beating and robbing!
Jiang Tao: You go back first. I’ll find Han Ling.
Han Ling: Secretary Song?
Song Secretary: No need! I’ve searched all Marxist-Leninist works, no quotes about the “Three Directives as the Key Link”!
Han Ling: You just didn’t put in effort!
I told you many times, hold a Standing Committee meeting to discuss this. Similar quotes will do!
Jiang Tao is a worker; how much Marxism-Leninism does he understand?
Hmm, see? This line is excellent! Powerful!
Song Secretary: Secretary Han, your level is clear!
Han Ling: Yes, you weren’t serious enough.
Today is September 17th?
Song Secretary: Yes.
Han Ling: Hmph! Nine years ago, also today, Jiang Tao led people to rebel, right?
Song Secretary: Yes, exactly, that kid led the trouble!
Han Ling: Hmph hmph hmph hmph!
See, this is ironclad proof! History will prove my innocence!
Hmph hmph hmph hmph!
Nine years, history played a big joke on us. Today, it ends!
Han Ling: Ha ha ha ha, sit, sit, sit.
Jiang Tao: Comrade Han Ling, an old worker, because he disagreed with your so-called rectification, was removed and criticized!
This issue of the journal, for publishing a few anti-revisionist articles, was confiscated and sealed!
Zhong Dachuang sold a few copies, and you arrested him. Why?
What crime did they commit?
Han Ling: What crime? Hmph. Today against this, tomorrow against that, now against the Provincial Committee, against the Central Committee!
First telling university students to become peasants, then attacking professors, now opposing the “Three Directives as the Key Link"!
Look, what did Zhong Dachuang write?
He said some people, under the banner of achieving the Four Modernizations, oppose limiting bourgeois rights.
Who does that refer to?
Jiang Tao: Anyone treating bourgeois rights as their lifeline!
Is it a crime to criticize bourgeois rights?
Han Ling: Criticize bourgeois rights?!  Hmph, how revolutionary!
But do you have enough material foundation? Can you launch satellites? Solve automation and mechanization? What will future society be like?
The Cultural Revolution messed things up for nine years. Tens of millions of people in the province, what are they hoping for?
They want more pork and vegetables in their baskets, bigger homes, better clothes.
Jiang Tao: Your words give me inspiration!
Here’s another famous line:
“Revolutionary impulse alone is not enough.”
Han Ling: Exactly, that’s empty talk, revolution only in fantasy!
Jiang Tao: Listen further:
“We also need a good dish of Goulash, books and decent housing,"
"We should have more food, more good dishes, schools, homes, and ballet.” -Khrushchev
Comrade Han Ling, you want to pin the blame for not modernizing or ignoring people’s lives on good comrades!
But it’s precisely them who traversed thousands of miles along the Yellow River, finding solutions for sediment control!
It’s them, day and night, working to produce machinery to manage the Yellow River!
t’s them, carrying in their hearts tens of millions of people along the riverbanks!
It’s them—good comrades removed, criticized, and suppressed by you!
Han Ling: Comrade Jiang Tao, do you understand? We must achieve the Four Modernizations!
Jiang Tao: We want modernization, yes,
but we know if we don’t conduct class struggle, don’t implement proletarian dictatorship, don’t limit bourgeois rights,
Party will turn revisionist, our country will change color!
Even that so-called socialist country modernizes, but as their satellites go up, red flags come down!
There, the revolutionaries live in prisons, wearing handcuffs and shackles!
Han Ling: Don’t go too far. What we call “Three Directives as the Key Link combines politics and economics, and it has theoretical grounds.
Listen to what Lenin said:
“Viewing problems politically and economically has equal value.
Both can be applied. Politics and economics must both be at the core.”
Selected Works of Lenin, 1972 edition, Volume 4, page 441.
The old masters weren’t wrong, were they?
Comrades should read more Marxist books, or you’ll make big jokes of yourselves.
Jiang Tao: Hahahahaha!
Go on. Keep reading.
Comrade Han Ling, what you just read was Lenin quoting Bukharin.
Right after that comes Lenin’s ruthless criticism of Bukharin!
Lenin said that claiming politics and economics have equal value
forgets the most basic knowledge of Marxism!
Hahahaha! Comrade Han Ling, are you treating Bukharin as your revolutionary leader?
Han Ling: Th-this was an accidental oversight!
Jiang Tao: No, this was no accident at all.
It shows that those who push restoration and regression instinctively follow opportunism!
Han Ling: You’re outrageous!
You know who proposed the “Three Directives as the Key Link!
Keep this up, and you’d better think about the consequences.
The Three Directives all come from Chairman Mao!
Jiang Tao: Chairman Mao always emphasizes class struggle as the core.
You selectively quote him to oppose proletarian dictatorship and the Party’s basic line.
You use Chairman Mao’s banner to oppose Chairman Mao himself!
Sister Zhao: Well said!
Jiang Tao: Sister Zhao!
Sister Zhao: We’ve already received hundreds of letters from workers, peasants, and soldiers.
The hearts of the people and Party members reject your approach.
Most Standing Committee members were furious that you seized the journal without discussion.
They demand reporting this to Chairman Mao and the Central Committee.
Also print 50,000 more copies to deliver Mao Zedong Thought to the masses!
Jiang Tao: Sister Zhao, haha!
Sister Zhao: Old Geng has been reinstated. Dachuang has returned to school.
Jiang Tao: That's great!
Han Ling: Contact Vice Premier Deng in Beijing!
Lyrics: The Yellow River roars and rushes,
I lift my head and face wind and rain.
The revolutionary spark was sown by Chairman Mao…
I brandish my spear across thirty thousand miles,
Enduring bitter struggle, ranging freely through the vast fields of battle and labor.
Riding the wind, treading the waves—
Towards communism...
Song Secretary: Xiaofang, why did you come back alone?
Your father said a car would pick you up.
Auntie: Xiaofang, you’re back?
I heard your father plans to send you abroad to study.
He says to learn real skills.
Han Xiaofang: Where is my father?  Auntie: Fishing in the backyard.
Han Ling: As an old comrade, I tried to save him, to stop him from sinking deeper.
But things went against my wishes.
Qiao Boren: Yes, Secretary Han has shown him utmost kindness.
Wang Jian: Say it plainly. What exactly do you plan to do to Jiang Tao?
Han Ling: Old Wang, look at this. My record of calls with the Central Committee.
Comrade Deng criticized us for being indecisive and too soft.
Wang Jian: Temporary demotion—how is that different from removal?
Han Ling: You can interpret it yourself.
Jiang Tao has attacked veteran cadres for years. You suffered from it too. You should expose him boldly.
Wang Jian: Comrade Han Ling, isn’t this sowing discord?
For seven or eight years, we worked and studied together. He never suppressed me, or you, Qiao Boren.
He sincerely helped, encouraged, respected, and protected us.
In him, I see the finest qualities of new cadres forged by the Cultural Revolution.
I see a Communist with firm principles and fearless resistance to trends!
Why make such a decision? This is persecution!
Han Ling: Old Qiao, after removing Jiang Tao, abolish the open-door education sites immediately. Withdraw everyone from the dam project as well.
So, Wang Jian is unreliable too. Remove him together.
Qiao Boren: But he’s a veteran cadre.
Han Ling: He is disobedient. Old and new alike—remove them step by step.
Qiao Boren: Alright.
Han Ling: Tonight, assist Secretary Song. Hold an expanded Party committee meeting at the university.
Song Secretary: I will continue reading. Third: Comrade Zhang Hai of the Workers’ Propaganda Team is hereby removed from the post of Deputy Party Secretary of Yellow River University.
Comrades Huang Di, Li Meng, and Li Haiquan of the Workers’ Propaganda Team are removed from their posts as members of the University Party Committee,
and transferred back to their original work units.
We hope you will return to your factories and make greater contributions to boosting the national economy.
The education reform work previously under Comrade Zhang Hai will now be taken over by Xue Yaozong, Professor Xue.
Wang Jian: At least explain the reasons.
Qiao Boren: Isn’t it obvious? It’s to fully bring into play the role of senior professors.
Song Secretary: Exactly right. Completely correct.
All right, I will continue. Fourth:
Comrade Jiang Tao has sabotaged the Party’s policy toward intellectuals, raised ultra-left slogans at will,
put pressure on the Provincial Party Committee, opposed the implementation of the “Three Directives as the Key Link,”
opposed comprehensive rectification, and undermined stability and unity.
Therefore, the Provincial Party Committee has decided that Comrade Jiang Tao is to be sent down!
Comrade Qiao Boren will serve as Acting Party Secretary of Yellow River University!
Zhong Dachuang: This decision by the Provincial Party Committee is completely wrong!
Old Geng: Hmph! Pure slander and frame-up!
I protest this act of persecution and demand that the Provincial Party Committee revoke this decision!
Jiang Tao: Comrades, whether it’s nominal assignment or comprehensive rectification,
it all means one thing: everything we’ve done since the Cultural Revolution is being declared wrong!
And everything they did before the Cultural Revolution is being declared right!
Hmph! But they have forgotten one truth:
restoration and regression are always short-lived, while new things are invincible!
Our Party is a great, glorious, and correct Party. It has endured the test of ten line struggles,
standing firm like the pillar in the middle reaches of the Yellow River, ready to meet a thousand—ten thousand—challenges!
Song Secretary: Okey，okey...
Song Secretary: No, no, They’re applauding Jiang Tao—this situation is getting out of control!
Mm, yes, yes, that’s what I mean.
As long as we convey the leaders’ instructions, the masses will come to their senses.
All right, all right, Party Secretary Han, it’ll be done immediately.
Old man, stop applauding—you’ve been fooled!
Jiang Tao: Comrades, the next steps in the Party Committee’s work:
First, we must continue to firmly grasp class struggle as the key link,
seriously study the theory of the dictatorship of the proletariat throughout the college,
and unswervingly run the school as an instrument of proletarian dictatorship.
Second, we must uphold the direction of educational revolution and run schools with open doors.
Of the original 97 open-door education sites, not a single one will be closed, the doors must be opened even wider!
Those who agree with Comrade Jiang Tao’s proposal, raise your hands.
Song Secretary: Comrades, comrades, comrades—don’t fall for his trick!
Jiang Tao, stop being so stubbornly misguided!
To be sent down is your chance to repent!
He—he is inciting everyone to oppose the Central Committee!
Comrades, comrades, let me be clear: the decision I read has backing!
It was made in accordance with the spirit of Comrade Xiaoping’s directives!
Jiang Tao: Comrades, no matter how fierce the winds and waves, the Yellow River will never flow backward!
We must fight for the truth!
Comrade Jiang Tao!
Jiang Tao: Why does Qiao Boren dare to drag out again things that were thoroughly criticized and condemned seventeen years ago?
Why does Han Ling openly oppose the Cultural Revolution and overturn its verdicts? Can Deng Xiaoping represent the Party Central Committee?
Chairman Mao said: beware of revisionism, especially beware of revisionism emerging in the Central Committee!
Xiao Mei: Dad, people say you made a huge mistake.
They say you’re an ambitious schemer who wants to be a big official!
Jiang Tao: Dad doesn’t like tears, huh?
Xiao Mei: Dad, let’s go back to the factory!
Grandpa Geng and the others all like you. Mom says she’ll come get you and take you back to the factory!
Jiang Tao: Xiao Mei, go to sleep.
Xiao Mei: Mm.
Jiang Tao: Yumei, this is the first time you’ve come to pick me up, isn’t it?
The War of Liberation, the Great Movement to Resist America and Assist Korea—you sent me to the battlefield.
Collectivization, harnessing the Yellow River, the Anti-Rightist Movement, the Cultural Revolution—you sent me to fight every time.
But you’ve never come to bring me back from the battlefield.
Yumei: Old Jiang, going back to the factory is still making revolution. We workers will fight them together.
Jiang Tao: The working class ascended to the superstructure because Chairman Mao sent us there.
If Chairman Mao asked why we returned to the factory, what should we say?
Yumei: You love the Party and love Chairman Mao.
I know you’ve carried out the revolution through wind and rain.
But now people say you oppose the Provincial Party Committee, oppose the Party, oppose the Central Committee…
Jiang Tao: Do you believe that?
Half a century ago, Chairman Mao led our Party through repeated fierce struggles against erroneous lines.
Chen Duxiu, Liu Shaoqi, Lin Biao—all waved the banner of the Central Committee!
Can today’s Deng Xiaoping represent the Party Central Committee?  Yumei: Of course not!
Jiang Tao: But they still hold a great deal of power, from the center to the localities.
That’s where the complexity of the struggle lies!
We must unite with the broad masses and confront the revisionist line head-on!
Old Geng: Jiang Tao!
Jiang Tao: Comrade Old Geng, why are you here?
Old Geng: The comrades at the factory asked me to come see you!
Yumei: Oh—Uncle Geng!
Old Geng: Yumei, why are there people keeping watch downstairs?
Old Geng: Probably “guards” sent by Han Ling for me!
Old Geng: Damn scoundrels!
Last night they already announced your nominal assignment decision at the construction site—the workers didn’t give them the time of day!
The comrades at the factory discussed it and sent me here overnight to tell you to hold firm. The entire working class stands with you!
Jiang Tao: Comrade Old Geng!
Old Geng: Before I left, the comrades asked me to bring you this.
Jiang Tao: Comrades, follow me!
Comrade Old Geng, Comrade Old Geng, quick!
Comrade Old Geng, this red flag is stained with the blood of our working class!
We must forever occupy the battlefield of education!
We must launch uninterrupted attacks against the bourgeoisie!
Old Liu, old Jiang doing this—I’m really worried for him.
What are you afraid of? The sky won’t fall!
Won’t fall? Just wait and see. Jiang Tao is so arrogant—he won’t end well!
Who are you trying to scare? You work so hard for the capitalist roaders—what benefits do you get?
Old Jiang! Old Jiang!
Director Qiao has gone to Liujiadu to dismantle the site. Even the motorboats transporting equipment have been blocked!
Zhong Dachuang: How can that work? Without pontoon cranes, how can we transport anything up?
Jiang Tao: Let’s go—let’s take a look!
Auntie Tian: Auntie will ferry you over on a leather raft.
Qiao Boren: Comrades, dismantle faster—pack faster!
Get all the personnel and tents onto the first truck!
Hurry up! Hurry up! We don't have much time!
Professor Xue: Yes—hurry up!
Qiao Boren: Even if you don’t want to leave, you have to. These are orders from above!
Professor Xue: Exactly!
Xiao Hong, Shen Niu—stop dawdling!
Qiao Boren: Load it up!
Faster! Faster! Faster! Move it!
Faster!
Qiao Boren: Comrade Old Geng, goodbye!
Sorry to have caused you so much trouble. Please give us more valuable opinions!
Old Geng: Old Qiao means for me to say a few words. Fine—I’ll say a few words!
Qiao Boren: Keep it brief. The wind’s picking up—don’t let the students get soaked!
Old Geng: The students we send out won’t be ruined by a little rain!
Students, those of you studying water conservancy should also learn this:
learn to tell the wind’s direction—is it blowing from the southeast or the northwest? Do you go with the wind and waves first, or against the wind and waves first?
Qiao Boren: All right, that’s enough. That’s enough!
Old Geng: Pah! Students, let me continue what I was saying just now.
No matter how many bends the Yellow River makes, it always flows into the sea!
I believe that after weathering this storm, you will come back!
The Crowd: Comrade Old Geng!
Qiao Boren: What are you doing? What are you doing? First truck—drive off!
Jiang Tao: Don’t move!
Old Zheng, you finally came. And old Jiang.
Jiang Tao: Old Qiao, you want to shut down this site?
Yes.
The Party Committee has decided—no site is to be shut down!
Qiao Boren: Comrade Jiang Tao!
You should understand that right now I am presiding over the Party Committee’s work!
Jiang Tao: Then I ask you to follow the Party Committee’s resolution and lead everyone along Chairman Mao’s revolutionary line!
Qiao Boren: Jiang Tao, you—
Professor Xue, Professor Wen—we’re leaving!
Professor Wen: We’re not going the same road anymore!
Qiao Boren: Old Xue, let’s go!
Hmph!
Jiang Tao: Comrades!
Comrades!
In order to ensure that the first phase of the project is completed within three days,
all revolutionary teachers and students here are to concentrate at the dam construction site and fight a war of annihilation,
to realize Chairman Mao’s great call to get the Yellow River under control!
The motorboats are blocked—so what!
We’ll pull and haul by hand first, advancing straight into the wind and waves!
Song Secretary: Secretary Han, Secretary Han—Jiang Tao shows no sign of giving in at all.
Wang Jian is the same—still confronting us head-on!
Han Ling: Mm. All right.
Song Secretary: The construction site is plastered with big-character posters,
calling you capitalist-roaders isn’t enough anymore, they said “capitalist-roaders still on the road”!
Han Ling: How is it that they’ve dragged out that whole Cultural Revolution set again?
Qiao Boren: With Jiang Tao stirring things up like this, and with Wang Jian backing the open-door education sites, not a single one has been shut down.
Song Secretary: What’s even more serious is that the big-character posters say "we must beware of revisionism emerging in the Central Committee."
Han Ling: Hmph! These posters aren’t just aimed at me—they’re directly attacking Vice Premier Deng!
No wonder Vice Premier Deng criticized me for being soft!
Remove Wang Jian!
As for Jiang Tao—I’ll arrange a “suitable place” for him!
Dolma?
Dolma: Auntie! Jiang Tao has been taken away!
Auntie Tian: They’ve shown their malicious intent!
The Crowd: Let’s go! Hurry! Hurry! Hurry!
Voices: Jiang Tao!
Return-to-the-Village Corps
Jiang Tao: Return-to-the-Village Corps!
Auntie Tian: Return-to-the-Village Corps!
Thirty years ago, right under this old locust tree, Return-to-the-Village Corps also arrested people!
Back then, Han Ling was the regional Party secretary here. He said a new stage of “peace and democracy” had arrived.
When he came to our area, he ordered the disbandment of village militia units.
One night—one night—Return-to-the-Village Corps slipped into our village.
They burned and looted, and Pan Ling was seized by them too.
Back then, Jiang Tao was the head of our village’s Children’s Corps.
Ah ah!
Return-to-the-Village Corps: Where is he?
Over there! Chase him, you bastard!
Jiang Tao: Quick! Run that way!
Return-to-the-Village Corps: Get him! Where did that little brat run off to?
Finish him! Over there! Over there—quick!
FXXK!
Auntie Tian: Jiang Tao!
Blood — you’re hurt!
Auntie Tian: In these thirty years, people have walked very different roads.
Han Ling, whom Jiang Tao once saved, entered the city after Liberation and became a high official, and his heart drifted farther and farther away from the people.
He was involved in dismantling cooperatives, in the big push for household responsibility system, and in suppressing the Cultural Revolution!
Who would have thought—Han Ling, who himself was once arrested by the Return-to-the-Village Corps, becomes one today and seize Jiang Tao!
Zhong Dachuang: We must settle accounts with the capitalist-roaders!
Auntie Tian: Child, don’t cry! Fight them like Jiang Tao and Sister Zhao did!
Sister Zhao: Comrade Han Ling, ever since you were reinstated, everything you’ve done has stood in opposition to Chairman Mao’s revolutionary line!
Now you’ve even privately detained Comrade Jiang Tao—this violates Party discipline and state law!
Han Ling: Comrade Zhao Xin, you should know that Jiang Tao’s anti-Party, anti-Central stance is the essence of the problem!
Sister Zhao: Then put your so-called “essence” on the Provincial Party Committee agenda, and make it public to the people of the entire province!
Han Ling: Hmph! Jiang Tao dares to do this because he’s not isolated—someone has been backing him all along!
Sister Zhao: Hmph-hmph, that’s right! I’m backing him!
Digging out the backstage supporters—there’s nothing frightening about that. We crossed snow-capped mountains and grasslands following Chairman Mao.
If anyone insists on pushing an erroneous line—it won’t work!
Narration: Seven guards were replaced in succession; even the cook came under Jiang Tao’s influence.
Song Secretary: Secretary Han, we’ve interrogated him many times—he’s still that die-hard type. Nothing will come out of him.
Han Ling: Even if there are no results, we still have to try. Director Zhao has already filed several complaints to the Center, and the masses keep coming to make trouble.
Song Secretary: Then?
Han Ling: It’s fine. The initiative is still in our hands.
As long as he changes his stance, Old Lady Zhao’s appeals will be completely nullified!
Song Secretary: Heh heh heh heh heh—Comrade Jiang Tao!
Outrageous! Outrageous! Just look at how they’re handling this!
Party Secretary Han spoke to them several times, telling them not to put this on you—heh heh heh heh!
Jiang Tao: Just speak plainly! What new trick are you trying to pull today?
Song Secretary: No, no, no—today Party Secretary Han is personally here to see you.
Han Ling: Ah, Old Jiang!
Ha ha ha ha—how’s your health lately? Still good?
Jiang Tao: Very good! Your penal methods can't hurt me at all!
Han Ling: Hmph-hmph! Still as stubborn as ever!
Jiang Tao: Time to pin down a charge! Is my crime “anti-restoration,” or “opposing revisionism and preventing revisionism”?
Han Ling: Ah—let’s not talk about that. Let’s not talk about that!
Old Jiang, I know you. Didn’t we once have a bond of shared life-and-death, fighting side by side?
Jiang Tao: Back then we walked the same road, but our hearts were never aligned.
Isn’t meeting here today a clearer statement of our class relationship than sitting on the Provincial Committee’s sofas?
Han Ling: Don’t look at it that way, Old Jiang.
These past eight or nine years, I’ve realized one thing: old grudges should be resolved, not prolonged.
Jiang Tao: These past eight or nine years, I’ve also grasped one truth:
The struggle between the revolutionary camp and the capitalist-roaders is a life-and-death class struggle!
Han Ling: I advise you to face reality. With Vice Premier Deng presiding over the Central work, the overall situation is settled!
If you keep writing inspections like this, you’ll never have a future!
(Further discussion on the fact that the capitalist roaders are still on the capitalist path)
Jiang Tao: You’re determined not to follow Chairman Mao anymore!
Anyone who wants to bring down our Party will find it’s not that easy!
Han Ling: All right, all right, Old Jiang—don’t be so short-sighted!
I’m already over sixty years old. As long as you follow us, won’t it be you who takes over this Provincial Committee leadership in the future?
Jiang Tao: Despicable and shameless!
Get out of here!
Han Ling: Jiang Tao! Don’t try to play the hero!
Have you ever thought about this—when you silently disappear from this world, as someone who "oppose Party," how painful would it be?
You should know—you’re sitting in a proletarian prison cell!
Jiang Tao: You capitalist-roaders can turn the instruments of proletarian dictatorship into tools of bourgeois dictatorship!
As a Communist Party member, to sacrifice everything for the cause of communism fills me with supreme honor and happiness!
I firmly believe Marxism-Leninism will triumph! The communist ideal will certainly be realized!
Han Ling: Put that thing on him!
Jiang Tao: Han Ling, the revolutionary people will punish you!
(Writing a letter) Respected Chairman Mao: In our country of proletarian dictatorship, who can throw Communists into prison?
The Kuomintang cannot do it. Landlords and capitalists cannot do it. Yet the Party’s capitalist-roaders in power have done it!
You profoundly pointed out that when revisionism comes to power, it means the bourgeoisie has come to power.
I firmly believe that our great leader Chairman Mao will surely lead us in a massive counter-attack against revisionism…
Xiao Mei: Mom, will we be able to see Dad soon?
Yumei: Yes.
Sister Zhao: Yumei, don’t be sad. Isn’t everything better now?
Our great leader Chairman Mao has spoken for us!
Yumei: Yes… after hearing Chairman Mao’s words, I couldn't even sleep last night.
Sister Zhao: It’s been several months—so hard. I went to see him several times and they wouldn’t allow it.
Later I went to the Provincial Committee to find you—who would have thought they’d take you down too.
So vicious!
Xiao Mei: Mom, does dad work here now?
Mom, tell me—tell me!
Xiao Mei: Dad! We’re here to take you home!
Dad!
Jiang Tao: Sister Zhao!
Sister Zhao: Comrade Jiang Tao!
Jiang Tao.
Auntie Tian: Child, you’ve suffered so much!
Jiang Tao: Auntie.
Auntie Tian: The capitalist-roaders’ hearts are truly poisonous!
Yumei: Old Jiang.
Jiang Tao: Yumei.
Yumei: Now Chairman Mao has spoken for us.
Old Jiang—look!
Chairman Mao!
Background: Long live Chairman Mao!
Long live!
Jiang Tao: Long live Chairman Mao!
Jiang Tao: Heh-heh—now the situation is excellent! The masses are rising in a mighty surge!
Sister Zhao: Yes! That means we leading cadres must stand at the front of the movement!
Comrade Old Jiang—here are the materials for you.
Jiang Tao: I was just looking for you. Everything else is good—I changed two spots.
Tell them to seriously study the theory of proletarian dictatorship and firmly grasp the overall direction of criticizing Deng.
Sure!
Yao Mingli: Xiao Fang, forget about studying abroad.
As long as your father doesn’t fall, everything is manageable!
Jiang Tao: Xiaofang!
Yao Mingli: Jiang Tao—goodbye.
Xiaofang, I’ll wait for you tonight!
Han Xiaofang: All right!
Jiang Tao: Why did you come back?
Han Xiaofang: Something came up.
Jiang Tao: Do you really know him?
Han Xiaofang: Yao Mingli? What about him?
He’s from a worker background, studied in the Soviet Union, has real skills, and treats me quite well.
Jiang Tao: Xiaofang—you must stay alert around him.
In real class struggle, if someone refuses to align themselves with workers and peasants, counter-revolutionaries may very well align themselves with him.
Sister Zhao: Good—send it out immediately. We shall promote production through criticizing Deng.
Good!
Director Zhao, phone call from Beijing!
Old Geng: Old Jiang! You’re here—I’ve been looking everywhere!
All workers of the Yellow River Hydraulics Machinery Factory unanimously propose that the province-wide criticism assemblies be held right on the Yellow River dam,
and that we use the iron facts of flood-release and sediment discharge to criticize Deng Xiaoping!
Jiang Tao: Great! We’re thinking alike! Heh-heh—this way we both report success and criticize Deng!
Old Geng: Right—release the water first, then make speeches!
Both: Hahahahahaha!
Jiang Tao: Good! Let the Yellow River cheer for us!
OK, ok.
Sister Zhao: Chairman Mao and the Central Committee have repeatedly emphasized
that leading cadres must stand on the front line of struggle, taking the lead in exposing and criticizing.
The Central Committee’s care for cadres is truly meticulous—but unfortunately Han Ling won’t listen to a single word.
Yesterday I talked to him again—same as always.
Once Chairman Mao’s instruction was published, he collapsed and stopped working.
Jiang Tao: I think he goes all-out for revisionism, and falls “ill” whenever socialism is involved!
Hmph—says he’s sick, but he’s busier than ever lately.
Secretary Song has been really active recently.
Sister Zhao: Their abnormal activities are not isolated—
they’re closely tied to new developments in class struggle.
Look—this is the latest enemy situation report.
Class struggle is becoming more and more complex.
Secretary Song: Party Secretary Han, Qiao Boren and Professor Xue both said they had matters to attend to and couldn’t come.
They’re becoming harder and harder to invite.
Han Ling: Hmph—short-sighted rats! Do they think we’re finished?
Is Comrade Xiaoping still working or not?
Things are already stirring up in front of Tiananmen in Beijing—
and here, the smell of gunpowder is just as strong!
Song Secretary: Yes, Party Secretary Han. According to this enemy-situation report,
Yao Mingli has been frequently contacting Han Xiaofang.
Cheers！Cheers！
Crowd: Hey—the Chairman’s back!
Yao Mingli: Let me introduce everyone—this is the son of Provincial Party Secretary Han, Han Xiaofang.
Chatter
Biaozi: You still remember me, Biaozi, right? Ahahahaha! We used to vacation together!
Ha ha ha.
Then the Cultural Revolution came, investigations started—my old man suddenly became a traitor. Now it’s your old man’s turn!
Old Ke: Uh, I say, Han Xiaofang, we invite you to join our Committee for Saving the Four Modernizations.
Let’s take them on together!
Right now Secretary Han’s stance at the provincial level is extremely favorable to us.
Yao Mingli: Old Ke, once our cause succeeds, the “rightist” label on you can be exchanged for a ministerial crown!
Old Ke: Hahahaha! I’ve been waiting for this day!
Once it’s done, we hang Jiang Tao first!
Yes! Hang him!
What—scared?
Han Xiaofang: Didn’t you say you called me here to discuss realizing the Four Modernizations?
Nerd!
Hahahahahahahahahaha!
The Four Modernizations—haha!
First comes power!
They have began their move in front of Tiananmen!
We must also launch a big push under the banner of Deng!
In real class struggle, if a person refuses to align himself with workers and peasants, counter-revolutionaries may very well align themselves with him.
Stop! No one is allowed to go home tonight! We’ll discuss everything tomorrow morning!
Jiang Tao: Comrades, to ensure the success of the sediment discharge, we will conduct one more check before the mass meeting convenes.
Each group, report your readiness.
Crane ready!
Observation instruments ready!
Hydrological measurements ready!
Jiang Tao: Good! Ready...!
Yao Mingli: Don’t open the gates!
Don’t open the gates!
Fellow villagers! Fellow villagers!
If we open the tunnel’s bottom outlet,
this hillside will collapse!
The dam will fail!
Several counties downstream on the Yellow River will be destroyed!
All flooded by the Yellow River!
We will all be finished!
Chatter
Zhong Dachuang: Comrades!
This is complete rumor-mongering!
We have tested this hundreds of times, the dam will absolutely not collapse!
Chatter
Yao Mingli: Fellow villagers, I am from the provincial committee! I cannot speak against my conscience!
Open the tunnel bottom outlet and the dam will collapse!
Chatter
Party Secretary Han, out of concern for everyone’s lives and property, imported dredging ships from abroad!
But Jiang Tao refuses to use them!
Old Geng: Yao Mingli! Those dredging ships were bought by the provincial capitalist-roader Han Ling, following Deng Xiaoping’s instructions,
bought a few wacky foreign ships with huge amount of oil, and they are completely useless!
Yao Mingli, you know this very well. You have ulterior motives to bring up those dredging ships today!
Yao Mingli: Don’t listen to him! Party Secretary Han wants everyone to live a good life! Jiang Tao’s purpose is to strike at veteran cadres!
[Chatter]
Yao Mingli: Comrades! Today’s meeting is chaired by the Committee for Saving the Four Modernizations!
Old Geng: Yao Mingli, get down! What are you doing?
Zhong Dachuang: What is Committee for Saving the Four Modernizations?
Chatter
Secretary Song: I never expected trouble to break out on the dam. From the looks of it, the masses still support you very strongly!
Han Ling: Hehehe… Jiang Tao, let’s see how you’re going to clean this up!
Jiang Tao: Yes, yes—that’s right, Director Zhao. They’ve already openly raised the banner of the Committee for Saving the Four Modernizations.
Sister Zhao: Mm! Yes. We’ll take action according to the provincial committee’s predetermined plan!
Jiang Tao: Good!
Zhong Dachuang: Old Jiang, mobilize the militia immediately and arrest those bastards!
Jiang Tao: They must be arrested—but not immediately.
Zhong Dachuang: Then what do we do now?
Jiang Tao: Some of the masses have been misled. Two types of contradictions are mixed together. At moments like this, the more we must stay calm.
Think about it—why do they dare to so recklessly sabotage the criticism meeting? Why do they bring up Han Ling's name?
Zhong Dachuang: You mean the capitalist-roaders are backing them?
Jiang Tao: Exactly. Their heart is inside the Party!
Only by first exposing the capitalist-roaders can we educate the misled masses,
then isolate the small handful of counterrevolutionaries and subject them to ruthless suppression!
Zhong Dachuang: Good!
Jiang Tao: Wait. Go notify the militia command—have all units assemble and stand by. I’m going to the dam immediately!
Zhong Dachuang: Yes!
Counterrevolutionaries: Where’s Jiang Tao?!
Come out so we can beat Jiang Tao to death!
Jiang Tao! Jiang Tao! Come out!
Jiang Tao: What are you doing?!
Who sent you here?!
I am the representative of the poor and lower-middle peasants along both banks of the Yellow River!
Crowd: You’re a counterrevolutionary!
Jiang Tao: Comrades! Comrades! I now announce on behalf of the provincial committee, they are a counterrevolutionary organization!
What they are doing today is absolutely not an isolated incident!
In recent days, in front of Tiananmen in Beijing, a gang of counterrevolutionary rioters has been doing exactly the same thing!
Zhong Dachuang: Whoever dares to make trouble where Chairman Mao lives, we overthrow them!
Dolma: Whoever dares to make trouble at Tiananmen, we emancipated serfs will never allow it!
Crowd: Resolutely suppress counterrevolutionaries!
Defend the Central Committee!
Defend Chairman Mao!
Han Xiaofang: Old Jiang, I was wrong!
Firmly support Secretary Han！
Secretary Han！Secretary Han！
Jiang Tao is suppressing revolutionary masses!
Han Ling: Don’t arrest people—let them go!
Firmly support Secretary Han! Firmly support Secretary Han!
Han Ling: Comrades! I arrived one step too late! The emergence of such a situation—I bear responsibility!
Today’s meeting was approved by the provincial committee. Therefore, any interference with this meeting is wrong!
Counterrevolutionary A: Damn it, why are you singing this tune too?
B: You don’t know shit—listen carefully!
Han Ling: Different opinions—and even erroneous opinions—can emerge among the masses. Free debate should be allowed!
Jiang Tao: You are speaking on behalf of the enemy! We absolutely do not grant counterrevolutionaries freedom of speech!
Han Ling: Jiang Tao, a new cadre must learn how to correctly treat mass movements. I have lessons in this regard.
Jiang Tao: Last year, during the rightist reversal wind, you carried out brutal suppression of revolutionary masses. Did you speak then about “correct treatment”?
Today a small handful of counterrevolutionaries want to seize power from the Party, and you call it a mass movement! Which class are you protecting, exactly?!
Han Ling: I am still the provincial Party secretary! Without my order, no militia may be mobilized!
Jiang Tao: Once counterrevolutionary disturbances appear on the dam, immediately deploy militia for suppression, this was decided by the provincial standing committee!
Han Ling: On what basis did you make this decision?! This violates Party discipline and state law!
Jiang Tao: On what basis? It’s written in Marx’s books, Lenin’s books, and Chairman Mao’s books: the dictatorship of the proletariat must be exercised over the bourgeoisie!
This is our Party discipline and state law! Without this protective shield, proletarians would die! This is the lesson of history!
Yumei: Old Jiang, look at these reactionary leaflets—they’re vicious!
This is their Open Letter to the People of the Whole Province!
Jiang Tao: Han Ling, they write reactionary leaflets, viciously attack Chairman Mao, split the Central Committee, and openly support Deng, they are not "revolutionary mass"!
All militia units—move out immediately!
Sister Zhao: Comrade Jiang Tao must suppress them resolutely!
These mobs here are extremely rampant, we must resolutely implement the dictatorship of the proletariat!
Militia: Take them away! Move!
Crowd: Long live the dictatorship of the proletariat!
Long live the Communist Party of China!
Long live Chairman Mao!
Jiang Tao: Comrades! A small handful of counterrevolutionaries want to manufacture a Hungarian-style counterrevolutionary incident on our soil!
They can only bring about their own destruction under the iron fist of the dictatorship of the proletariat!
Today’s facts teach us: we must deepen the criticism of Deng,
and carry the struggle against the rightist reversal wind through to the end!
Otherwise, counterrevolutionaries in society, relying on capitalist-roaders in the Party,
can openly use violence to seize power from the Communist Party!
Recently, our great leader Chairman Mao pointed out:
in carrying out the socialist revolution, if you don’t know where the bourgeoisie is,
it is inside the Communist Party, the capitalist-roaders in power within the Party, the capitalist-roaders are still taking the road!
Song Secretary: Jiang Tao is targeting you.
Han Ling: Jiang Tao, I will report you to the Central Committee!
Jiang Tao: The “Central Committee” you speak of is nothing but Deng Xiaoping!
But what decides China’s fate, are the hundreds of millions of heroic people tempered by the Great Proletarian Cultural Revolution!
Long live Chairman Mao!
Sister Zhao: Comrade Jiang Tao, I bring you extremely great news!
The Central Committee and Chairman Mao have issued two resolutions of major historical significance!
Jiang Tao: Excellent! Announce them immediately!
Sister Zhao: Everyone, quiet down!
Now announcing the Central resolutions!
Comrades, I report to you extraordinarily great news!
The Central Committee and Chairman Mao have issued two resolutions of major historical significance:
First: The Resolution of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China appointing Comrade Hua Guofeng
as First Vice Chairman of the CPC Central Committee
and Premier of the State Council of the People’s Republic of China!
Crowd: Long live Chairman Mao!
Long live Premier Hua Guofeng!
Second: The Resolution of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China to remove Deng Xiaoping from all Party and state positions!
Crowd: Long live Chairman Mao!
Long live the Communist Party of China!
Long live Chairman Mao!
Resolutely support the two Central Committee resolutions!
Deeply criticize Deng Xiaoping’s counterrevolutionary revisionist line!
Jiang Tao: Comrades!
Our heroic revolutionary people—
like the endlessly surging furious waves of the Yellow River—
will sweep all the filth and silt that block history’s advance...
...into the vast ocean!
Let us, generation after generation, follow closely our great leader Chairman Mao,
and launch one hundred times, one thousand times, ten thousand times great counterattacks against the bourgeoisie! Open the gates!